<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Canadian Cities</string>
    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="cities">Cities</string>
    <string name="add_city">Add New City</string>
    <string name="no_saved">You have no saved cities currently</string>
    <string name="all_cities">All Cities</string>
    <string name="canadian_cities">Canadian Cities</string>

    <!--City Descriptions-->
    <string name="toronto_d">Toronto is the most populous city in Canada
        and the capital city of the Canadian province of Ontario.
        Toronto is an international centre of business, finance, arts, sports and culture,
        and is one of the most multicultural and cosmopolitan cities in the world.</string>
    <string name="ottawa_d">Ottawa is the capital city of Canada.
     It is located in the southern portion of the province of Ontario,
        at the confluence of the Ottawa River and the Rideau River.
        As of 2021, Ottawa had a city population of 1,017,449 and a metropolitan population of 1,488,307,
        making it the fourth-largest city and fourth-largest metropolitan area in Canada.
    </string>
    <string name="vancouver_d">Vancouver is a major city in western Canada,
        located in the Lower Mainland region of British Columbia.
        The Metro Vancouver area had a population of 2.6 million in 2021, making it the third-largest metropolitan area in Canada. Greater Vancouver,
        along with the Fraser Valley, comprises the Lower Mainland with a regional population of over 3 million.
        Vancouver has the highest population density in Canada, with over 5,700 people per square kilometre,
        and fourth highest in North America (after New York City, San Francisco, and Mexico City).
    </string>
    <string name="calgary_d">Calgary is the largest city in the Canadian province of Alberta.
        As of 2021, the city proper had a population of 1,306,784 and a metropolitan population of 1,481,806.
        Calgary is situated at the confluence of the Bow River and the Elbow River in the southwest of the province,
        in the transitional area between the Rocky Mountain Foothills and the Canadian Prairies.
    </string>
    <string name="winnipeg_d">Winnipeg is the capital and largest city of the province of Manitoba in Canada.
        The city is named after the nearby Lake Winnipeg; the name comes from the Western Cree words for "muddy water" – winipīhk.
        The region was a trading centre for Indigenous peoples long before the arrival of Europeans; it is the traditional territory of the Anishinabe (Ojibway),
        Ininew (Cree), Oji-Cree, Dene, and Dakota, and is the birthplace of the Métis Nation.
    </string>
    <string name="quebec_d">Quebec City is the capital city of the Canadian province of Quebec. As of July 2021,
        the city had a population of 549,459, and the metropolitan area had a population of 839,311.
         It is also the second-largest city in the province, after Montreal.
        It has a humid continental climate with warm summers coupled with cold and snowy winters.
    </string>
    <string name="montreal_d">Montreal is the second most populous city in Canada, the tenth most populous city in North America,
        and the most populous city in the province of Quebec. Founded in 1642 as Ville-Marie, or "City of Mary", it is named after Mount Royal,
        the triple-peaked hill around which the early city of Ville-Marie was built.</string>
    <string name="hamilton_d">Hamilton is a port city in the Canadian province of Ontario.
        Hamilton has a population of 569,353, and its census metropolitan area,
        which encompasses Burlington and Grimsby, has a population of 785,184.
        Traditionally, the local economy has been led by the steel and heavy manufacturing industries.
        During the 2010s, a shift toward the service sector occurred, such as health and sciences.
        Hamilton is home to the Royal Botanical Gardens, the Canadian Warplane Heritage Museum,
        the Bruce Trail, McMaster University, Mohawk College, and Redeemer University.
    </string>
    <string name="edmonton_d">Edmonton is the capital city of the Canadian province of Alberta.
        Edmonton is situated on the North Saskatchewan River and is the centre of the Edmonton Metropolitan Region,
        which is surrounded by Alberta\'s central region.
        The city anchors the northern end of what Statistics Canada defines as the "Calgary–Edmonton Corridor", a region spanning between Edmonton and the city of Calgary,
        Alberta’s largest city, which includes the many smaller municipalities between the two.</string>
    <string name="saskatoon_d">Saskatoon is the largest city in the Canadian province of Saskatchewan.
        It straddles a bend in the South Saskatchewan River in the central region of the province.
        It is located along the Trans-Canada Yellowhead Highway, and has served as
        the cultural and economic hub of central Saskatchewan since its founding in 1882 as a Temperance colony.</string>
    <string name="kitchener_d">Kitchener is a city in the Canadian province of Ontario,
        about 100 km (62 mi) west of Toronto. It is one of three cities that make up the Regional Municipality of Waterloo and is the regional seat.
        Kitchener was known as Berlin until a 1916 referendum changed its name. The city covers an area of 136.86 km2,
        and had a population of 256,885 at the time of the 2021 Canadian census.</string>
    <string name="halifax_d">Halifax is the capital and largest municipality of the Canadian province of Nova Scotia,
        and the largest municipality in Atlantic Canada. As of 2022, it is estimated that the population of the Halifax CMA was 480,582,
        with 348,634 people in its urban area. The regional municipality consists of four former municipalities that were amalgamated in 1996:
        Halifax, Dartmouth, Bedford, and Halifax County.</string>
    <string name="kelowna_d">Kelowna is a city on Okanagan Lake in the Okanagan Valley in
        the southern interior of British Columbia, Canada. It serves as the head office of
        the Regional District of Central Okanagan. The name Kelowna derives from the Okanagan word kilawna,
        referring to a grizzly bear. Kelowna is the province\s third-largest metropolitan area (after Vancouver and Victoria),
        while it is the seventh-largest city overall and the largest in the Interior.</string>
    <string name="victoria_d">Victoria is the capital city of the Canadian province of British Columbia,
        on the southern tip of Vancouver Island off Canada\s Pacific coast. The city has a population of 91,867,
        and the Greater Victoria area has a population of 397,237. The city of Victoria is the seventh most densely
        populated city in Canada with 4,406 inhabitants per square kilometre (11,410/sq mi)
        Victoria is the southernmost major city in Western Canada and is about 100 km (62 mi)
        southwest from British Columbia\s largest city of Vancouver on the mainland.
        The city is about 100 km (62 mi) from Seattle by airplane, seaplane, ferry,
        or the Victoria Clipper passenger-only ferry, and 40 km (25 mi) from Port Angeles,
        Washington, by ferry Coho across the Strait of Juan de Fuca.</string>
</resources>